safestyle-windows.co.uk 2018-11-18

# Privacy Policy | Safestyle UK

## How we use your information

This privacy notice tells you what to expect when HPAS Ltd t/a Safestyle UK collects personal information. It applies to information we collect about: 

  * Visitors to or websites;
  * People who use our services – those who request a quotation or purchase from us;
  * Job applicants and our current & former colleagues;
  * Your Rights;
  * How to contact us. 

## Visitors to our website

When someone visits <https://www.safestyle-windows.co.uk/> we use a third party service, Google Analytics, to collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. This information is only processed in a way which does not identify anyone. We do not make, and do not allow Google to make, any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website. If we do want to collect personally identifiable information through our website, we will be up front about this. We will make it clear when we collect personal information and will explain what we intend to do with it. In addition to Google Analytics we use other third party services to collect details about specific user interactions and behaviours. VWO and Hotjar are both used to enable us to find out how our website visitors interact with the website to assist with further development. Again, this information is only processed in a way which does not identify anyone. The website <https://www.safestyle-windows.co.uk/> is built using Sitecore, a content management system and experience platform, which also powers our website search function. 

## Webpages containing video content

Our video content is embedded into our pages using Wistia video hosting. This enables us to collect additional information about a visitor’s interaction with the video content on each page and assist with further development of our video content. Information collected by Wistia does not personally identify anyone. 

## Third party website widgets and functionality

We use additional widgets from third party review sites Trustpilot and Feefo to embed recent customer reviews and feedback scores into our website pages. These widgets may use cookies to gain statistical data and measure traffic from our pages as well as the geographical area of visitors. Their privacy policies can be found at <https://legal.trustpilot.com/end-user-privacy-terms> and <https://www.feefo.com/business/gb_en/privacy-policy>

## Use of cookies by the Safestyle UK

You can read more about how we use cookies on our [Cookies Page](https://www.safestyle-windows.co.uk/cookie-policy/) Common cookies on our site are listed in the table below; 

Cookie

| 

Page

| 

Reason  
  
---|---|---  
https://www.safestyle-windows.co.uk | Safestyle website pages | To find the number of visitors to various parts of the website and visitor behaviours  
https://www.vars.hotjar.com | Safestyle website pages | To enable us to analyse the behaviours of our website visitors in greater detail  
https://www.google.com | Manufacturing > Explore our Factory  | Enables the use of Google Maps/Google Earth’s 360° streetview tour  
https://bid.g.doubleclick.net | Various pages | Track visitor sources and behaviours such as requesting a quote  
https://platform.twitter.com | Jobs & Opportunities | To enable sharing of positions on the Twitter social media platform  
https://4632612.fls.doubleclick.net | Various pages | Track visitor sources and behaviours such as requesting a quote  
https://backend.safestyle.co.uk | Various pages  | A standard PHP session created during a site visit that does not store any personal information  
https://fast.wistia.com | Pages with embedded video content | Enables us to add video content and find out how users interact with our video content  
  
## People who contact us via social media

We use Freshdesk (software of a third party provider Freshworks) to manage our social media interactions. Their Privacy Policy can be found at the following link - <https://www.freshworks.com/privacy/>

## People who call our helpline

When you call Safestyle's helpline we collect Calling Line Identification (CLI) information. We use this information to help improve its efficiency and effectiveness. We record some calls for training, security and monitoring purposes and notes may be taken by the person receiving the call to assist in the purpose of your call. Calls that are captured by voice-recording may be retained for up to 12 months. 

## People who email us

We use Transport Layer Security (TLS) to encrypt and protect email traffic. If your email service does not support TLS, you should be aware that any emails we send or receive may not be protected in transit. We will also monitor any emails sent to us, including file attachments, for viruses or malicious software. Please be aware that you have a responsibility to ensure that any email you send is within the bounds of the law. 

## People who use our LiveChat service

We use a third party provider, LiveChat Inc, to supply and support our LiveChat service, which we may use to handle customer enquiries in real time. If you use the LiveChat service we may collect your name, email address and the contents of your LiveChat session. This information will not be shared with any other organisations. You can request a transcript of your LiveChat session if you provide your email address at the start of your session or when prompted at the end. 

## People who use Safestyle UK’s services

Safestyle UK manufactures sells and installs windows, doors and conservatories to consumers. We have to hold the details of the people who have requested service in order to provide it. To deliver services under the guarantee, we will need to retain some personal information of customers for the period of the guarantee and any subsequent period during which there might be any liability. However, we only use these details to provide the service the person has requested and for other closely related purposes. For example, we might use information about people who have requested a quotation to carry out a survey to find out if they are happy with the level of service they received or to offer additional products and services via telephone. When people do not wish to subscribe to our services, they can cancel their subscription at any time and are given an easy way of doing this. During the processing of orders it may be necessary to pass contact details of customers to third parties to facilitate the delivery of services. Examples of when this would be done are when scaffolding is required, third party surveys are necessary or to process queries and complaints. We pass details of all installations to FENSA Ltd who register the work with each Local Authority as appropriate and customer details are also passed to the GGF Group for the provision of the Insurance Backed Guarantee. The FENSA registration and Insurance Backed Guarantee processes are necessary and required for compliance purposes following the installation of our products. 

## Job applicants and our current & former employees, agents and contractors

Safestyle UK is the data controller for the information you provide during the process unless otherwise stated. If you have any queries about the process or how we handle your information please contact us at [privacy@safestyle.co.uk](mailto:privacy@safestyle.co.uk). 

### What will we do with the information you provide to us?

All of the information you provide during the process will only be used for the purpose of progressing your application, fulfilling our obligation within your contract or to fulfil legal or regulatory requirements if necessary. We will not share any of the information you provide during the recruitment process with any third parties for marketing purposes or store any of your information outside of the European Economic Area. The information you provide will be held securely by us and/or our data processors. We will use the contact details you provide to us to contact you to progress your application. We will use the other information you provide to assess your suitability for the role you have applied for. 

### What information do we ask for, and why?

We do not collect more information than we need to fulfil our stated purposes and will not retain it for longer than is necessary. The information we ask for is used to assess your suitability for employment or engagement, depending on the role applied for. You don’t have to provide what we ask for but it might affect your application if you don’t. All calls to and from Safestyle UK’s offices may be recorded for monitoring and training purposes. 

### Application stage

We ask you for your personal details including name and contact details. We will also ask you about your previous experience, education, referees and for answers to questions relevant to the role you have applied for. Our recruitment team and selected members of HR and managers relevant to the recruitment process will have access to all of this information. You will also be asked to provide equal opportunities information in an anonymised format. This is not mandatory information – if you don’t provide it, it will not affect your application. This information will not be made available to any staff outside of our recruitment team and HR team, including hiring managers, in a way which can identify you. Any information you do provide will be used only to produce and monitor equal opportunities statistics. 

### Short-listing

Our recruitment team, HR and hiring managers shortlist applications for interview. 

### Assessments

We might ask you to participate in assessment days; complete tests or occupational personality profile questionnaires; and/or to attend an interview – or a combination of these. Information will be generated by you and by us. For example, you might complete a written test or we might take interview notes. This information is held by Safestyle UK and may also be held by a third party involved in administering the tests. Where a third party is involved their privacy and data retention policies will be explained to you. If you are unsuccessful following assessment for the position you have applied for, we may ask if you would like your details to be retained in our talent pool for a period of six months. If you say yes, we would proactively contact you should any further suitable vacancies arise. 

### Conditional offer

If we make a conditional offer of employment we will ask you for information so that we can carry out pre-employment checks. You must successfully complete pre-employment checks to progress to a final offer. We are required to confirm the identity of our staff, their right to work in the United Kingdom and seek assurance as to their trustworthiness, integrity and reliability. You will therefore be required to provide: 

  * Proof of your identity – you will be asked to attend our office with original documents, we will take copies.
  * Proof of your qualifications – you will be asked to attend our office with original documents, we will take copies.
  * You will be asked to complete a criminal records declaration to declare any unspent convictions.
  * We may request a Basic Criminal Record check via the Disclosure and Barring Service, which will verify your declaration of unspent convictions.
  * We will contact your referees, using the details you provide in your application, directly to obtain references.
  * We will also ask you to complete a questionnaire about your health. This is to establish your fitness to work.

If we make a final offer, we will also ask you for the following: 

  * Bank details – to process salary payments, expenses and other payments as necessary
  * Emergency contact details – so we know who to contact in case you have an emergency at work.

All of the above information will be held by secure electronic means except where this is impossible / impractical in which case it will be held in a secure paper format. All details will be used only for the purpose that they were requested and will not be shared with third parties without your explicit consent. All employee records, except those where there is a statutory obligation to retain them for a longer period will be deleted/destroyed six years after the termination of your employment. 

### Post start date

Our Code of Conduct sets out the minimum standards expected of all personnel, whether engaged on an employed or self-employed basis. Any personal information of others that you process during and as a consequence of your engagement with Safestyle UK must only be done in accordance with the company’s legitimate instruction and the data protection laws relevant to the UK. You will at no time own such data and must not retain or use it in any capacity beyond your contractual purpose. When you cease to be engaged by Safestyle UK you must not retain or use any such personal information. If you are provided with, or have use of a company vehicle, you will need to provide your driving licence details and submit to verification through the DVLA as a condition of eligibility to such use. Tracking devices may be installed into vehicles for safety and security & to enable the vehicle to be located, as well as to provide information relating to driving style and behaviours, with a view to encouraging safer driving practices which has associated benefits in reductions in insurance premiums payable. Where tracking devices are fitted all data from them will be collected and stored. All collected and stored data will be held in a secure electronic location and access will only be granted once a justification has been raised and approved by the Head of Transport. 

### Use of data processors 

Data processors are third parties who provide elements of our recruitment service for us. We have contracts in place with our data processors. This means that they cannot do anything with your personal information unless we have instructed them to do it. They will not share your personal information with any organisation apart from us. They will hold it securely and retain it for the period we instruct. 

### Pension

If you work with us on an employed basis, your details will be provided to Informed Financial Planning who are the administrators of Safestyle UK’s pension scheme. You will be auto-enrolled into the pension scheme and details provided to Royal London will be your name, date of birth, National Insurance number and salary. Your bank details will not be passed to Royal London at this time. 

### Health Management

Once we make you a conditional offer, we will ask that you complete a questionnaire which will help to determine if you are fit to undertake the work that you have been offered, or advise us if any adjustments are needed to the work environment or systems so that you may work effectively. This form will be supplied to you directly for completion and reviewed by the HR department. The form will be stored in a secure electronic location accessible only by the HR department. Should there be any concerns with the information that is supplied on your medical questionnaire you will be contacted by a member of the HR team and with your agreement we may enlist the support of an appropriate and approved occupational health provider. Where any employee, either during the offer stage or during the course of their continuing employment is referred to any occupational provider the individual will be entitled to with hold consent for information to be shared with us; and will also have the right to view any reports before they are sent to us. The occupational health provider will explain to you what data they collect about you and the purpose for which they use it. Some work within our manufacturing site requires health monitoring of hearing and blood to protect the vital interests of workers. Further details will be available to those who are required to undergo any such health monitoring. 

### How long is the information retained for?

If you are successful, the information you provide during the application process will be retained by us as part of your employee file for the duration of your employment plus 6 years following the end of your employment. This includes your criminal records declaration, fitness to work, records of any security checks and references. If you are unsuccessful at any stage of the process, the information you have provided until that point will be retained for 6 months from the closure of the campaign. Information generated throughout the assessment process, for example interview notes, may be retained by us for 6 months following the closure of the campaign. Equal opportunities information is retained for 6 months following the closure of the campaign whether you are successful or not. Networx will provide us with management information about our recruitment campaigns. This is anonymised information which tells us about the effectiveness of campaigns, for example, from which source did we get the most candidates, equal opportunities information for monitoring purposes. This anonymised information will be retained for 6 years from the end of the campaign. 

### How we make decisions about recruitment?

Final recruitment decisions are made by hiring managers and members of our recruitment/HR team. All of the information gathered during the application process is taken into account. 

### Individual responsibilities

Individuals are responsible for helping the organisation keep their personal data up to date. Individuals should let the organisation know if data provided to the organisation changes, for example if an individual moves house or changes their bank details. Individuals may have access to the personal data of other individuals and of our customers and clients in the course of their engagement. Where this is the case, the organisation relies on individuals to help meet its data protection obligations. 

### Individuals who have access to personal data are required:

  * to access only data that they have authority to access and only for authorised purposes;
  * not to disclose data (whether inside or outside the organisation) except to individuals who have appropriate authorisation;
  * to keep data secure (for example by complying with rules on access to premises, computer access, including password protection, and secure file storage and destruction);
  * not to remove personal data from the organisation's premises, or (without permission/clearance) devices containing or that can be used to access personal data, without adopting appropriate security measures (such as encryption or password protection) to secure the data and the device; and
  * not to store personal data on local drives or on personal devices that are used for work purposes.

Failing to observe these requirements may amount to a disciplinary offence, which will be dealt with under the organisation's disciplinary procedure. Significant or deliberate breaches of this policy, such as accessing colleague or customer data without authorisation or a legitimate reason to do so, may constitute gross misconduct and could lead to dismissal without notice. 

## Your rights

Under the UK’s Data Protection law, you have rights as an individual which you can exercise in relation to the information we hold about you. 

### Access to personal information

Legislation provides the right of access to personal data at reasonable intervals so that anybody can be aware of, and verify, the lawfulness of the processing – the right of access. Safestyle UK tries to be as open as it can be in terms of giving people access to their personal information. Individuals can find out if we hold any personal information by making a ‘data subject access request’ under the UK’s data protection laws. If we do hold personal information about you we will: 

  * Give you a description of it;
  * Tell you why we are holding it;
  * Tell you who it could be disclosed to; and
  * Let you have a copy of your personal information being processed in an intelligible form, but not necessarily copy documents with non-personal information within which your personal data might be contained;
  * Where possible the length of time we will hold it;
  * We will redact personal information of others unless they have explicitly consented to it being passed to you, as well as company sensitive and other information that is not your personal information, as deemed appropriate.

Responses to Data Subject Access Requests will be made within one month from receipt of the request, with any necessary extension up to a further two months being communicated to the requester, with an explanation as to why that is necessary. To make a request to Safestyle UK for any personal information we may hold you need to put the request in writing addressing it to our Privacy Office at the address provided below, or by emailing your request to [privacy@safestyle.co.uk](mailto:privacy@safestyle.co.uk). To ensure we continue to ensure the confidentiality of your information, you will need to provide sufficient verification as to your identity prior to any information being released. If we do hold information about you, you can ask us to correct any mistakes (Right of Rectification) by, once again, contacting the Privacy Office. Where you object to processing and there are no overriding legitimate grounds for the processing or you withdraw consent on which processing is based and there are no other legal grounds for processing then where no exemption exists you have the right to the erasure of that personal data. There are circumstances where you may not have a right of erasure, such as Safestyle’s need to comply with a legal obligation or in the establishment, exercise or defence of a claim and Safestyle UK will communicate any such circumstances with you as may be appropriate to your request. You have a certain rights to restriction of processing of personal data: 

  * if you believe it to be inaccurate and for the time it takes for Safestyle to verify its accuracy;
  * Where processing is unlawful, but you prefer restriction of rocessing rather than erasure;
  * If Safestyle no longer needs the personal data for the purposes of processing, but you require it for the establishment, exercise or defence of a legal claim;
  * You have objected to processing pending the verification that the legitimate grounds of Safestyle to continue processing override your grounds of objection.

You have the right to object to your information being processed for direct marketing purposes, which includes profiling to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing. Your data will not be retained for the sole purpose of being able to identify you for the purposes of data subject access rights. 

### Links to other websites

This privacy notice does not cover the links within this site linking to other websites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit. 

## Changes to this privacy notice

We keep our privacy notice under regular review. This privacy notice was last updated on the 17th May 2018. 

## Complaints or queries

Safestyle UK tries to meet the highest standards when collecting and using personal information. For this reason, we take any complaints we receive about this very seriously. We encourage people to bring it to our attention if they think that our collection or use of information is unfair, misleading or inappropriate. We would also welcome any suggestions for improving our procedures. This privacy notice was drafted with brevity and clarity in mind. It does not provide exhaustive detail of all aspects of Safestyle’s collection and use of personal information. However, we are happy to provide any additional information or explanation needed. Any requests for this, or indeed associated complaints, should be sent to the Privacy Office at the address below or via email to [privacy@safestyle.co.uk](mailto:privacy@safestyle.co.uk). 

## How to contact us

If you want to request more information about our privacy policy you can [email us](mailto:privacy@safestyle.co.uk) or write to: Privacy Office Safestyle UK Style House 14 Eldon Place Bradford West Yorkshire BD1 3AZ
